<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Massimo Meert</title><link>https://masmeert.github.io/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Massimo Meert</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://masmeert.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>blog test 1</title><link>https://masmeert.github.io/posts/kr-1-2/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://masmeert.github.io/posts/kr-1-2/</guid><description>Lesson 2 있다: To have This usage of 있다 in Korean is an adjective. Sentences with adjectives cannot act on objects, thus you cannot have a word with the particle ~을/를 attached to it if the predicating word in a sentence is an adjective.
To get around this, we can attach ~이/가 to the object instead in sentences with 있다. To indicate the thing that a person “has” in sentences with 있다.</description><content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="lesson-2">Lesson 2</h1>
<h2 id="있다-to-have">있다: To have</h2>
<p>This usage of 있다 in Korean is an <em>adjective</em>. Sentences with adjectives cannot act on objects, thus you cannot have a word with the particle ~을/를 attached to it if the predicating word in a sentence is an adjective.</p>
<p>To get around this, we can attach ~이/가 to the object instead in sentences with 있다. To indicate the thing that a person “has” in sentences with 있다.</p>
<ul>
<li>저는 가방이 있어요 = I have a backpack.</li>
<li>저는 차가 있어요 = I have a car.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="indicating-a-place-or-time-에">Indicating a place or time: ~에</h2>
<p>~에 denotes a place or time, it can therefore be used twice in a sentence.
“I went to the park at 10:00” would have ~에 attached to both &ldquo;park&rdquo; and &ldquo;10:00&rdquo;.</p>
<h2 id="있다-to-be-at-a-location">있다: to be at a location</h2>
<p>있다 can also be used to indicate that something/someone is at a location.</p>
<ul>
<li>저는 학교에 있어요 = I am at school.</li>
<li>저는 캐나다에 있어요 = I am in Canada.</li>
</ul>
<p>We can also use position words to indicate specifically where someone/something is with respect to another noun.</p>
<ul>
<li>안 = inside</li>
<li>위 = on top</li>
<li>밑 = below</li>
<li>옆 = beside</li>
<li>뒤 = behind</li>
<li>앞 = in front</li>
</ul>
<p>These words are placed after a noun to indicate where an object is with respect to that noun. The particle “~에” is then attached directly to the position words. For example:</p>
<ul>
<li>저는 학교 앞에 있어요 = I am in front of the school.</li>
<li>개는 집 안에 있어요 = The dog is inside the house.</li>
<li>고양이는 의자 밑에 있어요 = The cat is under the chair.</li>
<li>식당은 은행 옆에 있어요 = The restaurant is next to the bank.</li>
</ul>
<h2 id="이가-as-a-subject-marker">~이/가 as a subject marker</h2>
<ul>
<li>고양이<strong>는</strong> 집 뒤에 있어요 = The cat is behind the house.</li>
<li>고양이<strong>가</strong> 집 뒤에 있어요 = The cat is behind the house.</li>
</ul>
<p>~이/가, like ~는/은, is added to the subject of the sentence. In some situations, there is no difference in meaning or feel between adding ~이/가 or ~는/은 to the subject.</p>
<p>However ~는/은 also has a role of indicating that something is being compared with something else. In our example, the is only one sentence which gives the listener no context as to what &ldquo;the cat&rdquo; is compared with. However if I were to say &ldquo;The dog is in the house, and, the cat is behind the house&rdquo; the context fits the situation.</p>
<p>The good thing is, even if you make a mistake with the usages of ~이/가 and ~는/은, 99.9% of the time, the listener will be able to understand exactly what you are trying to express.</p>
]]></content></item></channel></rss>